Finding Aid for Frank Knox Papers, 1907-1910 and 1934-1938
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Frank Knox papers 1907-1910 and 1934-1938
Knox, Frank, 1874-1944.
6 linear ft. and 1 oversize folder
851630 Aa 2; Da Oversized
Newspaper publisher, manager of Chase S. Osborn’s campaign for governor in 1910, vice presidential candidate in 1936. Correspondence, 1907-1910 and Addresses, 1934-1938.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection came from two principal sources. In 1938, Col. Knox (donor no. 467 ) donated copies of his addresses. The correspondence was taken from the papers of Chase S. Osborn (donor no. 238 ). Other materials came from Mr. And Mrs. Donald Adams (donor no. 857 )
The collection is open to research.
Frank Knox was born in Boston on January 1, 1874. While still a boy, his family moved to Grand Rapids, Michigan. He attended Alma College, but interrupted his studies to enlisted in the Spanish-American War. Discharged when he contracted malaria, Knox accepted a position with the Grand Rapids Herald. In 1902, he and a printer of his acquaintance purchased the Evening Journal in Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan. A year later, they changed the name of the paper to the Evening News.
Knox was a progressive Republican who aligned himself with fellow Sault journalist Chase S. Osborn whom he had met in 1901. When Osborn ran for governor in 1910, Knox was his campaign manager, and following his nomination, he became chairman of the Republican State Central Committee. In 1912, Knox left the state to take over the Manchester Leader in New Hampshire.
Knox's subsequent career included ownership of the Chicago Daily News, vice presidential candidacy with Alfred Landon in 1936, and Secretary of the Navy (1940-1944).
The Frank Knox papers consist of two series: Correspondence and Addresses. The Correspondence series dates from 1907 to November 1910 and was donated by Chase S. Osborn. These are the papers from Osborn's campaign for governor, 1909-1910, and detail the close relationship between Osborn and Knox. The second series of Addresses was donated by Col. Knox in 1938, then at the Chicago Daily News, and concern his interest in public affairs, the New Deal, and his own campaign as vice presidential candidate in 1936.
Subjects:
Elections--Michigan--1910.; Landon, Alfred M. (Alfred Mossman), 1887-1987.; Michigan--Politics and government--1899-1916.; Michigan--Politics and government--1929-1938.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860; Presidents--United States--Election--1936.; Republican Party (Mich.); United States--Politics and government--1933-1945.; Governors--Michigan.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.
- Correspondence
  - 1907-January 1910, 75 folders (Box 1)
  - February-March 1910, 51 folders (Box 2)
  - April 1910-June 1910, 86 folders (Box 3)
  - July 1910, 46 folders (Box 4)
  - August 1910, 64 folders (Box 5)
  - September 1910-November 1910, 48 folders (Box 6)
- Addresses
  - March 1934 (Box 6)
  - June-September 1935 (Box 6)
  - October-December 1935 (Box 6)
  - January 1936 (Box 6)
  - August 1936 (Box 6)
  - September 1-15, 1936 (Box 6)
  - September 16-30, 1936 (Box 6)
  - October 1-15, 1936 (Box 6)
  - October 16-31, 1936 (Box 6)
  - January-June 1938 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous campaign addresses (Folder Da)
    (sheets from newspapers)